had some crazy polynomial function like
this and you need to know what is f of
2. traditionally the way you'd solve
this is you take all this and plug in 2
for the x's and then bring down all the
other stuff figure out what each of
these terms is equal to and then add or
subtract them all together and you get
three it would have taken a little bit
of time to figure it all out there's
another method you can do called
synthetic substitution you make a little
bar like this but the number you're
going to plug in outside here and then
put the coefficients including the
negative values right here so this is
how you set up the synthetic
substitution now to perform this
synthetic substitution all we're going
to do is add multiply add multiply add
multiply add multiply three plus zero is
three two times three is six negative
six plus six is zero two times zero is
zero negative one plus zero is negative
one two times negative 1 is negative two
three plus negative two is one two times
one is two negative four plus two is
negative two two times negative 2 is
negative four seven plus negative 4 is 3
and that is our answer and that's the
same answer we got up here this is
synthetic substitution for polynomials
it will always work and for large
polynomials it's usually easier than
this method how exciting